People who repeatedly give unwanted advice can be well-meaning and genuinely want to help.
有些人一再提出不受欢迎的建议，他们可能是出于好意，真心想要帮忙。
Others might do this out of a sense of self-worth around the ability to influence others.
另一些人这样做，则可能是出于一种自我价值感，而这种价值感与影响他人的能力挂钩。
One study found that people with a high tendency to seek power were more likely to give advice than those with an opposite tendency.
一项研究发现，追求权力的倾向很强的人比倾向相反的人更有可能提出建议。
Under the guise of unselfishness, people may be driven to give you unwanted advice because it makes them feel powerful or in control.
人们可能会打着无私的幌子，受某种内驱力驱使而给你提出不受欢迎的建议，因为这样做让他们觉得自己有权势，或者能掌控局面。
They may not be fully aware of this drive, however.
不过，他们自己可能并没有完全意识到这种内驱力。
These people may also display a problematic degree of emotional vulnerability, becoming upset very quickly, and taking a long time to calm down.
这些人还可能表现出情绪上的脆弱，而且到了成问题的程度：一下子就心烦意乱，又要过很久才能平静下来。
It is possible that their emotions were only validated in childhood when they were at their loudest, encouraging them to adopt responses to discomfort that are excessive in most situations.
有可能他们在童年时，情绪只有在表达得最激烈的时候才会得到认可，这促使他们在面对不适时采取一种反应方式，而这种方式在大多数情况下都是过激的。
When someone is giving advice in order to make themselves feel more powerful, there is underlying anxiety to their behavior that recipients of the advice tend to notice.
一个人为了让自己觉得更有权势而提建议时，其行为背后潜藏着焦虑，而收到建议的人往往会察觉到这种焦虑。
It can be tempting in this situation to react harshly to the advice giver and to accuse them of being manipulative, but this approach might produce an undesired result.
在这种情况下，你可能会忍不住严厉回应提建议的人，指责对方爱操纵别人，但这种做法可能会带来你不希望看到的结果。
If the act of giving advice is contributing actively to someone’s feelings of self-worth, an outright rejection may be perceived as a threat, activating their fight-or-flight response, possibly causing them to double down on their validation-seeking behavior, or leading to a larger conflict.
如果提建议这一行为正切实地增强着某人的自我价值感，那么对方可能会把直截了当的拒绝视为威胁，进而激活其“战斗或逃跑”反应，这可能使其在寻求认可的行为上变本加厉，或者引发更大的冲突。
The key is to validate without over-identifying.
关键在于既认可对方，又不过度认同。
You can let them know that you have heard them and appreciate where they are coming from without taking on the potentially damaging narrative that you could not have gotten by without their help.
你可以让对方知道，你听到了他们的意见，也理解他们的出发点，同时又不接受这样一种可能有害的说法：要不是有他们的帮助，你根本不可能应付过去。
You had better say something like, “Thanks for the idea.
你最好说些类似这样的话：“谢谢你出的主意。
I have my own plan for handling this, but I really appreciate your perspective and will take it into consideration.
这件事怎么处理，我有自己的打算，不过真的很感谢你的看法，我会把它考虑在内的。
Can I let you know when I need help in the future?”
等以后我需要帮忙的时候再告诉你，可以吗？”
If you have trouble setting boundaries tactfully, prioritize working on your own ability to self-regulate.
如果你难以得体地设定界限，那就要优先下功夫提高自己的自我调节能力。
As uncomfortable as it may make you continuously receiving unwanted advice, if you can respond with compassion, the situation will likely be defused much faster.
尽管不断收到不受欢迎的建议可能会让你很不舒服，但如果你能以同情心回应，局面很可能会缓和得快得多。
Though it is usually not the intended outcome of giving unsolicited advice, many who receive it often feel stressed, offended, or simply annoyed by unwanted suggestions.
许多人收到不请自来的建议后，常常会因这些不受欢迎的提议而感到有压力、被冒犯，或者纯粹是心烦，尽管这通常并不是提出这类建议想要达到的结果。
Setting a boundary in this regard, if you feel you need one, is perfectly reasonable and something that can bring you increased emotional safety.
如果你觉得有需要，在这方面设定界限是完全合理的，而且能让你在情绪上更有安全感。
It is best to set boundaries in a way that takes into account the individual’s underlying reasons for doing what they are doing, to avoid unnecessary conflict and more stress.
设定界限时，最好考虑到对方这样做的深层原因，以免引发不必要的冲突、带来更多压力。